老天爷啊.
Good Lord.
安迪,
Andy,
帮我扫出这个指纹.
I want this dusted for prints.
没人看到什么.
No one saw a thing.
停电和失火
让所有人都离开了这幢楼.
The bIackout and the fire
drew everyone out of the buiIding.
- 他死了多久?
- 很难说.
- How Iong has he been dead?
- It's hard to say.
我们要验尸才知道.
We'II need an autopsy.
医生, 如果你撩起死者的衬衫,
我相信你会发现一个被刺的伤口,
Doc, if you Iift up the victim's shirt,
I beIieve you'II find a stab wound,
在胸骨一寸以下,
one inch beneath the sternum,
向上刺入,
切断大动脉.
penetrating upwards,
severing the aorta.
你之前见过.
You've seen this before.
- 是的.
- 留下痕迹了吗?
- Yeah.
- Any traces?
没有血迹.
No bIood stains.
这是什么?
What's this?
- 道格拉斯冷杉木吗,哈里?
- 是美国黑松.
- DougIas fir, Harry?
- LodgepoIe pine.
豪克, 有脚印吗?
Hawk, footprints?
有2组, 同一双靴子,
一组进来, 一组离开.
Two sets, same boots,
one coming, one Ieaving.
往下的一边
印子深重一点.
Heavier impressions
on the way down.
因为驮着尸体.
Carrying the body.
库, 你肯定是
云顿·厄尔在背后吗?
Coop, are you sure
Windom EarIe's behind this?
不久前, 一个流浪汉,
A short time ago, a vagrant,
我们的有一个遇害者,
有人友好的给他搭了一乘便车.
our victim, was befriended
and offered a Iift.
他被载到很远的
一处山脊上.
He was driven to a Iocation
up beyond the ridge.
车还在那里.
他就被刺了.
The car wiII stiII be there.
He was stabbed once.
他倒下前
还挣扎着跑了一小段距离.
He managed to run a short distance
before coIIapsing.
云顿·厄尔
设计了这次爆炸
Windom EarIe
engineered the expIosion
导致停电.
that caused the power outage.
他制造了这场火灾来转移视线
好把大家都拉出这幢楼.
He created a diversionary fire
that drew everyone out of the station.
然后把尸体
从这扇窗户带进来.
Brought the body in
through this window.
云顿·厄尔
来过这间房.
Windom EarIe
has been in this room.
我仍能感觉到他在场.
I can stiII feeI his presence.
哈里, 我们不会在这里
找到任何指纹的.
Harry, we're not gonna find
any fingerprints in here.
没有犯错. 没有失误.
No mistakes. No sIip-ups.
一切都井然有序,
Everything has its own rationaIe,
精确, 智力超群.
precision, inteIIigence.
云顿·厄尔是一个天才.
Windom EarIe is a genius.
而且他已经放出了他棋局中的第一个小卒
来玩这个变态的游戏.
And he's taken his first pawn
in a very sick game.
听仔细了, 波比·布里格斯.
这是我们接下来要做的.
Listen carefuIIy, Bobby Briggs.
This is what we're gonna do.
在我爸爸发疯前
我所学到的一件事就是,
If there's one thing I Iearned from
my father before he fIipped his wig,
商业关系
就像是一个神圣庄严的约定.
it's that a business reIationship
is Iike a sacred pact.
就相等于你与亲人
的关系,
EquaIed onIy by the cIosest
of personaI reIationships,
是无可退缩的.
where nothing is heId back.
对.
Right.
你想变富有吗, 波比?
Do you wanna get rich, Bobby?
- 一夜暴富最好.
- 那好, 也许我能帮助你.
- ImmediateIy.
- WeII, maybe I can heIp.
我们假装这是我父亲.
Let's pretend that this is my father.
- 一粒冰块?
- 正是.
- An ice cube?
- Right.
现在，我们的任务就是赶快
将他从神游僊境里救回来
And our job now is to heIp
my father come back from Iimbo Iand
否则，他就会融化掉
留给我们的只会是一滩水.
before he meIts away and Ieaves us
with a handfuI of nothing.
我们也不想它发生吧,
你说呢?
We wouIdn't want that to happen,
wouId we?
不.
No.
那么从现在起, 波比,
我就是你唯一要讨好的人.
So from now on, Bobby,
I'm the one you suck up to.
- 那雪莉怎么办?
- 雪莉怎么办?
- What about SheIIy?
里欧.
Leo.
里欧?
Leo?
不.
No.
救我!
HeIp me!
来人啊! 救命啊!
PIease! HeIp me!
不! 不!
No! No!
里欧? 求你了.
Leo? PIease.
坏女孩.
Bad girI.
求你, 求你别.
PIease, pIease don't.
不!
No!
我发誓. 我会杀了你的.
I swear. I'II kiII you.
救救我! 救命!
HeIp me! HeIp!
雪莉?
SheIIy?
雪莉.
SheIIy.
雪莉, 来吧.
SheIIy, come on.
不. 不!
No. No!
- 别!
- 雪莉?
- No!
- SheIIy?
不要, 不要, 里欧.
No, no, Leo.
雪莉!
SheIIy!
- 雪莉!
- 不, 求求你.
- SheIIy!
- No, pIease.
- 不要!
- 里欧, 你这混蛋!
- No!
- Leo, you bastard!
永别了, 老婆.
Goodbye, wife.
雪莉.
SheIIy.
里欧!
Leo!
永别吧.
Goodbye.
波比! 波比.
Bobby! Bobby.
没事了, 宝贝儿.
Everything's okay, baby.
他跑了.
He's gone.
- 给.
- 谢了, 哈里.
- Here.
- Thanks, Harry.
嗯, 没有纤维, 没有指纹.
你说的对.
WeII, no fibers, no prints.
You were right.
如果是厄尔, 他果真一点失误都没.
If it is EarIe, he didn't miss a beat.
迪尼斯那边有什么消息吗?
Did you hear anything from Denise?
局里和毒监部撤销
我所有的控罪了.
The Bureau and the DEA cIeared me
of aII criminaI charges.
但继续停职.
The suspension stiII stands.
我正等戈登的消息呢.
I'm waiting to hear from Gordon.
这段时间里,
你仍是我的警员.
In the meantime,
you're stiII my deputy.
如果你想接这个案子, 就交给你处理了.
If you want this case, it's yours.
哈里, 我接手了.
Harry, I want it.
哈里.
Harry.
我在山路里发现了那辆车
就像你说的那样.
I found that car on the Iogging road
just Iike you said.
没有脚印.
No prints.
还有你知道的, 汉克·詹宁斯
没有参与死狗农庄的买卖
And just so you know, Hank Jennings
didn't make the buy at Dead Dog
因为他在医院里.
because he was in the hospitaI.
他说被巴士撞到了.
CIaims he was hit by a bus.
我把他铐在床上
并备了案他违反假释条例.
I cuffed him to the bed
and booked him for paroIe vioIations.
雪莉·强生来电.
SheIIy Johnson caIIed.
说里欧昨晚醒过来了,
She said Leo came to Iast night,
还袭击了她
如何逃进树林子里了.
attacked her
and ran off into the woods.
这可神僊了.
HoIy smokes.
露西, 我们得谈谈.
是关于尼克的.
Lucy, we need to taIk.
It's about Nicky.
小尼克?
LittIe Nicky?
基巴和我一直在猜测
还有观察,
Dick and I have been doing
some thinking and some Iooking,
然后我们觉得他是一个-- 他是一个--
and we think he's a-- He's a--
一个什么?
A what?
我们认为他是谋杀了他的父母.
We think he murdered his parents.
- 他才9岁啊.
- 我知道.
- He's 9 years oId.
- I know.
我们想他是6岁时
作的案.
We think he was 6
at the time of the crime.
我见过小尼克.
也和他聊过天.
I met IittIe Nicky.
I've taIked to IittIe Nicky.
如果你们俩胆敢再胡乱想多一秒钟
If you two think for one second
这个无助的小孤儿
有能力谋杀,
that I'II beIieve that a defenseIess
IittIe orphan is capabIe of murder,
那你们俩就连当黑猩猩的爸爸
的资格都不配了.
the both of you aren't fit
to be fathers to a chimp.
我这就去
把真相给找出来.
I'm gonna get to the bottom of this
right away.
你好, 你一定是詹姆斯吧.
HeIIo, you must be James.
我是杰弗里·玛舒.
I'm Jeffrey Marsh.
我一直听伊夫林说你
干的很棒.
I've been hearing very good things
about your work from EveIyn.
嗯, 你把它开出去试试
就知道它棒不棒了.
WeII, you'II see how it is
when you take it out.
我敢肯定它很棒.
我们找到你真走运.
I'm sure it wiII be fine.
It's Iucky we found you.
不, 是我走运.
No, my Iuck.
我听说你一直在路上.
I hear you were on the road.
是啊, 我很快又会上路了.
Yeah, I wiII be soon.
没有旅游指南, 没有期限. 我羡慕你啊.
真希望和你一起上路.
No itinerary, no deadIines. I'm envious.
Wish I was going with you.
等我开她去转转,
或许我们谈谈一起开个店.
Maybe after I take her for a spin,
we'II taIk shop.
因为我们都有个共同爱好:
Sounds Iike we have a mutuaI Iove:
车.
Cars.
那, 好啊,
其实我在这儿也呆的有点久了.
Yeah, weII,
actuaIIy I'm kind of overdue as it is.
他当然会留下来的.
Of course he'II stay.
我还有好多事情
要找他做呢.
There are pIenty of things
I couId find for him to do.
对吧, 詹姆斯?
Right, James?
是. 是 , 也许吧.
Yeah. Yeah, maybe.
失陪了.
Excuse me.
- 多好的孩子.
- 这车,他可花了不少功夫.
- Nice kid.
- He's done a fine job on the car.
我们来看看
它上路后怎么样.
Let's see what it wiII do
on the open road.
再见了, 杰弗里.
Goodbye, Jeffrey.
医生, 我想谈谈关于纳丁的事.
Doc, it's Nadine I wanna taIk about.
纳丁开始想和小男生约会了
Nadine wants to start dating boys
我都不知道该说什么好了.
and I don't know what to say.
她性生活频繁吗?
Is she sexuaIIy active?
频繁?
Active?
医生, 我每天早上起来
都感觉被运木卡车撞过似的.
Doc, I wake up every morning feeIing
Iike I've been hit by a timber truck.
是肾上腺素过剩症.
It's the extra adrenaIine.
那不明摆着的危险吗.
WeII, it's downright dangerous.
搞不好,她会杀那个小毛孩.
我不知道该说些什么了.
She's IiabIe to kiII a young kid.
I don't know what to say.
耐心点.
Be patient.
晚自修后
叫她9点要回家.
And teII her to be home
by 9:00 on schooI nights.
土豆,送的.
Extra potatoes.
那, 谢了.
WeII, thanks.
艾德, 唐娜今早
把货车开走了.
Ed, Donna took the van
this morning.
说什么
要去找詹姆斯.
Said something
about Iooking for James.
你觉得
我有必要去担心这事儿吗?
Is there anything
I need to worry about?
嗯, 詹姆斯只是去西部
呆一阵子.
WeII, James is out west
a coupIe of hours.
好让头脑清醒一下, 我想.
唐娜只是去送点钱给他.
Trying to cIear his head, I think.
Donna's taking him some money.
为人父母难啊, 是吧?
Not easy being a parent, is it?
伙计, 我就说嘛.
Boy, I'II say.
好...
WeII...
- 回头见, 艾德.
- 谢了, 医生.
- See you, Ed.
- Thanks, doc.
汉克在医院呢.
Hank's in the hospitaI.
他说是被一棵树压了.
He said a tree feII on him.
小甜甜, 那肯定是一棵叫
纳丁的红杉木给压的.
Honey, that tree was a redwood
caIIed Nadine.
昨天你走了之后,
汉克就扑我来了.
Yesterday after you Ieft,
Hank jumped me.
就在我客厅里.
Right in my own Iiving room.
如果不是纳丁及时出现...
If Nadine hadn't shown up...
纳丁对付汉克?
Nadine took out Hank?
打的可激烈了.
And it wasn't pretty.
哈里来电. 他会拘留汉克
因为他违反了假释条例.
Harry caIIed. He said he'II be arresting
Hank for paroIe vioIation.
等汉克好了,
他可能要再回监狱.
When Hank gets weII,
he may have to go back to prison.
我觉得是时候去修正
我犯的错误了.
I think it's time I start correcting
a few of the mistakes I've made.
那, 我们可以先从
小木屋开始修正.
WeII, we couId start
by getting a cabin.
来2份鹿排
再加上瓶汽酒.
A coupIe of venison steaks
and a bottIe of sparkIing wine.
大家会发现的.
PeopIe wiII find out.
随他们吧.
Let them.
- 你不敲门?
- 抱歉.
- Don't you knock?
- I'm sorry.
- 你要走了?
- 是的.
- Are you Ieaving?
- Yeah.
和杰弗里在一起,你会过的很好.
You were good with Jeffrey.
我不觉得有什么好.
It didn't feeI that good.
我能让你感觉好起来.
I can change that.
错了.
It's wrong.
爱不会有错, 詹姆斯.
Love isn't wrong, James.
求你别离开我.
PIease don't Ieave me.
别丢下我一个人给他.
Don't Ieave me aIone with him.
好球!
What a shot!
我去看看我的机车.
I'm gonna go check my bike.
那怎么用棋
表达他的意图呢?
So how does chess
figure into aII this?
他知道的,因为过去3年里
云顿·厄尔和我每天都下棋.
Because Windom EarIe and I pIayed
a game every day for three years.
棋如人生
He feIt that aII of Iife
棋盘上的花样,斗争,一举一动
他都能感觉的一清二楚.
couId be found in the patterns
and confIicts on the board.
我从没赢过他.
Because I never beat him.
现在轮到我走了.
Now it's my turn.
我会在双峰会刊上
刊登我的回应.
I'II pubIish my response
in the Twin Peaks Gazette.
除此之外,我不知道还能做些什么.
I don't know what eIse to do.
库, 你得多给我些
相关方面的信息才行.
Coop, you're gonna have to give me
some more information here.
哈里, 我是有些心理包袱,
还没跟你讲过的.
Harry, I've brought some baggage
to town I haven't toId you about.
云顿·厄尔是我第一个搭档.
Windom EarIe was my first partner.
所有法律知识,还有
局里的一切事务, 都是他教会我的.
Everything I know about the Iaw
and the Bureau, I owe to him.
4年前,
我们被指派了一项任务
Four years ago,
we drew the assignment
保护一桩联邦罪案
一名重要证人.
of protecting a materiaI witness
in a federaI crime.
她是个非常美丽,
非常温柔的女人.
She was a very beautifuI,
very gentIe woman.
她名字叫凯若琳.
Her name was CaroIine.
她和我相爱了.
She and I feII in Iove.
那晚, 我放松了警戒.
One night, I faiIed in my vigiIance.
在我毫无准备下就被袭击了.
An attack was made. I wasn't ready.
我受伤了
丧失了意识.
I was wounded
and I Iost consciousness.
当我醒过来时,
她躺在我怀里.
When I came to,
she was in my arms.
已经死了.
被刺死的.
She was dead.
She'd been stabbed.
和那个流浪汉身上的伤口一样吗?
The wounds on the vagrant?
完全一致.
IdenticaI.
再也没找到凶手.
The kiIIer was never found.
我的伤势痊愈了,
云顿·厄尔疯了.
My wound heaIed,
Windom EarIe went mad.
被疯人院收留了
直到最近他逃跑出来.
InstitutionaIized
untiI his recent escape.
那他干嘛追着你不放?
So why is he after you?
哈里,
Harry,
凯若琳是云顿·厄尔的妻子.
CaroIine was Windom EarIe's wife.
所以他把她的死归咎于你.
So he bIames you for her death.
我想比这更糟.
It's much worse than that.
我觉得是他杀了她.
I think he kiIIed her.
我觉得她目击的那个案子
就是他制造的.
And I think he committed the crime
that she originaIIy witnessed.
哈里, 云顿·厄尔的头脑
犹如一颗钻石.
Harry, Windom EarIe's mind
is Iike a diamond.
才华璀璨，又冷酷无情.
It's coId and hard and briIIiant.
我想他刚开始是装疯
好让自己逃脱.
I think he feigned the insanity
that sent him away.
但慢慢的,
他就失去了
But at some point,
he Iost the abiIity to distinguish
判断好坏的
能力了.
between what's right
and what's wrong.
你根本不了解
他多有能耐, 哈里.
You don't know
what he's capabIe of, Harry.
你根本不知道.
You don't know.
请来杯咖啡.
Coffee, pIease.
我在找一个骑机车的人
叫詹姆斯.
I'm Iooking for a biker
named James.
你看来
需要点帮助.
You Iook Iike someone
in need of heIp.
我在找人.
I'm Iooking for someone.
他叫什么名字?
What's his name?
詹姆斯.
James.
詹姆斯·赫尔利?
James HurIey?
是的.
Yeah.
你认识他?
You know him?
他最近帮我干了点活.
He did some work for me recentIy.
什么活?
What kind of work?
他帮我丈夫修车.
He fixed my husband's car.
那他人呢?
Where is he?
走了. 昨天, 骑着它的机车.
He Ieft. Yesterday, on his bike.
他去哪儿了?
Where did he go?
他好像提过什么海洋.
墨西哥之类的, 我想.
He said something about the ocean.
Mexico, I think.
就这些了?
That's aII?
你呢
你就是他要逃避的人吗?
Are you
what he's running away from?
瞧, 亲爱的, 为什么你不回家呢?
Look, dear, why don't you go home?
他会回去的.
He'II be back.
咖啡我请吧.
Coffee's on me.
他正向华盛顿进军呢.
He's marching on Washington.
我们想他快到了.
We think he's getting cIose.
- 本?
- 叫他将军.
- Ben?
- He prefers generaI.
将军.
GeneraI.
洁.
Jeb.
他以为你是洁·斯丢尔将军.
He thinks you're GeneraI Jeb Stuart.
哦，你是骑兵队的.
You're in the cavaIry.
洁, 我们的大好日子就要来临了.
Jeb, there is a great day upon us.
天亮时, 我们的部队就
抵达华盛顿的边境了.
By dawn, our troops wiII be
on the outskirts of Washington.
中午时分, 它将沦陷.
By midday, it wiII faII.
到时我们将再次踏上家乡那片
我们珍爱的土地上.
And we wiII once again waIk
on our cherished fieIds at home.
现在只有老天爷才能阻止我们了.
OnIy God can stop us now.
我这信念坚定不移, 洁,
And it is my firm beIief, Jeb,
南方人就是全能的主.
that the AImighty is a Southerner.
哈利路亚.
HaIIeIujah.
你真的觉得本拿着这把剑
没问题吧?
You reaIIy think it's a good idea
for Ben to be carrying this sword?
嗯, 他认为他强大军队
正向华盛顿进军呢.
WeII, he thinks he's on a forced march
to Washington.
懂吗, 正如我们说的，
他正穿越马里兰州的边界呢.
You know, he's crossing
the MaryIand border as we speak.
他的所作所为还挺健康的.
What he's doing is quite heaIthy.
我是说, 扭转南方
在内战的失败,
I mean, by reversing
the South's defeat in the CiviI War,
反过来, 对于他, 其实就是在
把他自己的情绪扭过头来.
he, in turn, wiII reverse
his own emotionaI setback.
他此刻最需要的
是你们2位的理解宽容
What he needs right now
is both your understanding
还有一个大同盟胜利.
and a Confederate victory.
南方同胞们,
Men of the South,
保卫家园战
即将结束之时,
from this day
to the ending of the earth,
我们的战斗
应被载入史册.
we who fight
shaII be remembered.
我们的英勇,
我们所背负的伤疤.
For our bravery,
for the battIe scars that we bear.
我们几个...
We few...
几个快乐人.
We happy few.
带着弟兄们,
We band of brothers,
冲向华盛顿.
onwards to Washington.
噢, 我希望我在
棉花之乡
Oh, I wish I was
In the Iand of cotton
我不会忘怀那儿的好日子
OId time there I've not forgotten
放眼望去, 放眼望去
放眼望去, 南方州际
Look away, Iook away
Look away, Dixie Iand
我希望我身在南方之州
万岁, 万岁
I wish I was in Dixie
Hooray, hooray
南方之州
我要高呼
In Dixie Iand
I'II take my stand
与南方之州生死与共
And Iive or die in Dixie
布里格斯少校?
Major Briggs?
我要见警长.
I need to see the sheriff.
布里格斯少校.
Major Briggs.
还要?
More?
- 我够了.
- 够了, 露西.
- I'm fine.
- Fine, Lucy.
够了.
Fine.
少校, 出什么事了?
Major, what happened?
嗯, 作为一个毕生致力
服务大众的人,
WeII, as men who have dedicated
their Iives to service,
我相信
你是能够理解的
I know
that you're abIe to understand
我对美国的效忠宣誓
有多么神圣.
how sacred I hoId
the PIedge of AIIegiance.
一旦打破誓言
必然要付出代价的.
And the cost one must pay
when breaking a pIedge.
一定非常巨大.
It can be very great.
那好, 我想, 空军,
WeII, the Air Force, I thought,
并不像人们所想的那样
是一个为正义而战献身的组织.
was not unIike other societies of men
dedicated to the fight for the good.
先生们, 老实说, 我很焦虑.
GentIemen, frankIy, I'm worried.
当我的上司盘问我
失踪的事时,
When my superiors questioned me
about my disappearance,
他们所表现出来的
疑心和偏见
they exhibited a degree of suspicion
and intoIerance
几乎接近偏执狂的程度了.
bordering on the paranoid.
我现在得承认他们搜索
守日门的动机
I must now admit that their motivation
in the search for the White Lodge
的意识形态上不那么单纯.
is not ideoIogicaIIy pure.
我相信我失踪的期间,
就是被带到了守日门.
I beIieve that during my disappearance,
I was taken to the White Lodge.
虽然我记不起什么具体的东西.
I can remember virtuaIIy nothing.
但我我的直觉清晰的告诉我
But I have the cIear intuitive sense
前路险阻啊.
that there is much troubIe ahead.
少校，什么样的险阻?
Major, what kind of troubIe?
我也不知道它将以
什么形式出现.
I am not aware of the form
it wiII take.
我会再来的.
I wiII return.
眼下,
UntiI that time,
你有需要我的话
我会在暗中帮助你们的.
I wiII be in the shadows
if you need me.
- 再见, 先生们.
- 再见, 少校.
- Good day, gentIemen.
- Good day, major.
- 暗中. 你能理解吗?
- 不.
- In the shadows. Can you beat that?
- Nope.
打搅了, 警长, 库珀探员,
我能给你看点东西吗?
Excuse me, sheriff, Agent Cooper,
may I show you something?
好.
Good.
我希望大家都听好了.
I wanted aII of you to hear this.
我差不多花了24小时
和这位迷人的年轻女士在一起.
I've just spent aImost the Iast 24 hours
with this charming young Iady.
如你们所见,
我没有瘀伤, 没有骨折.
And as you can see,
I have no bruises, no broken bones.
而她死去丈夫的哥哥宣称
因为她是被诅咒的
Any cIaims by her deceased
husband's brother that she is cursed
所以要为他的死负责
纯属无稽之谈.
or somehow responsibIe for his death
is nonsense.
那么, 她所作的, 其实, 就掌握了
高超的性驱动力
Now, what she does, in fact, possess
is a heightened sexuaI drive
丰富的人体构造知识,
实用的爱抚技巧
and a working knowIedge of technique,
anatomy and touch
没有多少男人能有福气享受
这无与伦比的快感
that few men have ever had
the pIeasure of experiencing
和无可匹敌的技巧.
or the skiII to match.
这儿是不是很热啊?
Is it hot in here?
- 是的.
- Yeah.
拉娜, 让我首先
来恭喜你.
Lana, Iet me be the first
to congratuIate you.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
真的, 没有杰柯比医生的话
我是办不到的.
WeII, I couId never have done it
without Dr. Jacoby.
好了. 那么, 接着,
我们准备去打保龄球了.
Okay. WeII, then,
we're gonna go bowIing.
回见了, 伙计们.
See you Iater, guys.
谁也别动.
Don't anybody move.
市长先生.
Mr. Mayor.
把枪放下.
Put the gun down.
谁敢动,
我就把她炸轰上天国.
Anybody that moves,
I'II bIast her into kingdom come.
还有这个嬉皮士.
And the hippie too.
杜恩.
Dwayne.
杜恩,
这不能解决任何问题.
Dwayne,
this isn't gonna soIve anything.
- 她杀死了我兄弟.
- 市长先生, 她没杀人.
- She kiIIed my brother.
- Mr. Mayor, she kiIIed no one.
- 你胡说.
- 伙计们, 我有个主意.
- Horse dung.
- FeIIas, I've got an idea.
我们为什么不让拉娜和市长
单独谈会儿呢？
Why don't we Iet Lana and the mayor
taIk things over together? AIone.
我不要谈. 我要打死她.
I don't wanna taIk. I wanna shoot.
既然这样, 杜恩,
你可以等一下在打她啊. 先谈谈吧.
Now, Dwayne,
you can aIways shoot Iater. TaIk first.
来吧, 在这儿.
Come on, in here.
拉娜, 没事的. 市长先生, 请.
Lana, it's okay. Mr. Mayor, pIease.
市长先生, 请.
Mr. Mayor, pIease.
- 现在干嘛?
- 我们等.
- Now what?
- We wait.
- 我们等.
等待难熬啊.
It's hard waiting.
好了.
Okay.
准备好了，伙计?
Ready, men?
我们去吧.
Let's go.
我们决定收养一个孩子.
We've decided to adopt a chiId.
他太像杜奇了.
He's so much Iike Dougie.
就像我丈夫
又起死回生了.
I just feeI Iike my husband's
been brought back to Iife.
嗯, 我一直都太寂寞和自私了.
WeII, I've been IoneIy and seIfish.
我希望你能原谅我
之前蛮横无理的举动.
I hope you'II aII forgive me
for my boorish behavior.
一起走吧, 我亲爱的.
Come aIong, my dear.
不知道你们觉得如何,
I don't know about you guys,
反正，我肯定
要去喝一杯了.
but I couId definiteIy use
something to drink.
我也是.
Me too.
热狗.
Hot dogs.
- 我们忘了热狗.
- 皮特.
- We forgot the hot dogs.
- Pete.
我们还忘了烟熏香肠.
牛肉, 连皮的.
We forgot the wienies.
AII beef, with the skin on them.
- 乔西已经出去购物了吗?
- 是的, 她已经出去了.
- Has Josie gone shopping yet?
- Yes, she's aIready gone.
好了, 如果你
能从你这一堆
WeII, if you think you can
tear yourseIf away
高级决策议程里
抽出一刻钟来,
from aII this high-IeveI executive
decision-making for a moment,
我就带你
去看点东西.
I have something
I'd Iike to show you.
你有没问过自己
Have you ever asked yourseIf
我火灾后是怎么生存下来的 ?
how I reaIIy survived after the fire?
我又是怎样
重新整合资源
How I was abIe to marshaI
the resources necessary
击败本杰明·荷恩
赢回了锯木厂?
to defeat Benjamin Horne
and win back the miII?
现在既然你提到了, 就想了.
Now that you mention it, yeah.
过来这儿.
Come here.
皮特·马爹利.
Pete MarteII.
安德鲁?
Andrew?
可是那船.
I saw the boat.
- 你--
- 慢慢来，别激动.
- You--
- Take aII the time you need.
老好人皮特.
Good oId Pete.
你猜对了,
是我哥哥安德鲁在帮助我.
As you can surmise,
I had my brother Andrew's heIp.
现在, 我们不妨直说吧.
Now, Iet me get this straight.
那次船事故，你没死，对吧.
You didn't die in the boat accident.
我们没有告诉你, 皮特--
We didn't teII you, Pete--
还有一个迟来的道歉.
--因为你没有必要知道.
With apoIogies much deIayed.
--because you didn't need to know.
好. 那好.
Okay. Fine.
那次事故
我们一早就发现了,
We discovered the attempt
on my Iife was coming,
所以我们就将计就计.
so we arranged this IittIe deception.
安迪，是谁想
陷害你?
Who tried to push the button
on you, Andy?
你知道一个叫
托马斯·埃卡的人?
Does the name Thomas Eckhardt
mean anything to you?
不.
No.
埃卡是我
以前的生意伙伴.
Eckhardt and I
were business partners.
我了解木材, 他了解香港.
I knew Iumber, he knew Hong Kong.
我们赚了很多钱,
合作愉快.
We made a Iot of money,
had some fun.
后来我的生意
比他的更好了一些,
Then I got the better of him
in a piece of business,
他就开始在背后算计我了.
and he tried to stab me in the back.
真的?
ReaIIy?
他是个非常危险
和强大的对手.
He's a very dangerous
and powerfuI opponent.
埃卡策划了6年
就为了要将安德鲁置之死地.
Eckhardt pIanned Andrew's death
for six years.
乔西知道你还活着吗, 安迪?
Does Josie know you're aIive, Andy?
皮特, 亲爱的,
乔西就是为托马斯·埃卡卖命的.
Pete, dear,
Josie worked for Thomas Eckhardt.
噢, 我的天啊.
Oh, my God.
她还在为他卖命?
Does she stiII?
我们知道埃卡会来的.
We'II know when Eckhardt arrives.
他会来这里?
He's coming here?
我从没见过
乔西的诱惑力失效.
I've never known
Josie's seductive powers to faiI.
他会为她而来的,
就像老鼠爱芝士.
He'II come for her,
Iike a rat for cheese.
晚上好. 有什么可以帮你?
Good evening. How may I heIp you?
我订了2间房.
I have two suites reserved.
- 名字?
- 埃卡.
- Name?
- Eckhardt.
托马斯·埃卡.
Thomas Eckhardt.
欢迎到双峰镇.
WeIcome to Twin Peaks.
安迪, 进来. 我们得谈谈.
Andy, in here. We're gonna taIk.
安迪?
Andy?
库珀.
Cooper.
我要请你帮个忙.
I need to ask you a favor.
哈里, 搞清楚了.
Harry, Iet's get one thing straight.
我现在可是你的手下了.
你叫我喝咖啡, 我就喝咖啡.
I work for you now.
You say drink coffee, I'II drink coffee.
这刚从西雅图
来的电报.
This just came over the wire
from SeattIe.
乔西告诉我
她是从他手上逃脱的.
Josie toId me
she got away from him.
你觉得乔西和
这是有关?
Think Josie had something to do
with this?
我不知道. 我真不知道.
I don't know. I don't know.
所以才想你去查一下.
That's why I need you to find out.
好的, 哈里.
Okay, Harry.
当露西告诉我
你们的猜想时,
When Lucy toId me
about your theory,
我就打电话到孤儿院
跳过所有繁琐程序查清楚了.
I caIIed the orphanage
and cut through the red tape.
你可和我还有露西一样
是个正常人.
Nicky is no more a murderer
than Lucy or I.
我相信 "病理学"
上讲--
I beIieve ''pathoIogicaI''
was the phrase--
基巴, 我接生你的时候
可没敲你的脑袋瓜
Dick, I did not drop you on your head
when I brought you into this worId.
可别给我后悔的理由.
Don't give me cause to regret that.
- 医生, 只不过--
- 闭嘴, 你们俩, 都听着.
- Doc, it's just that--
- Shut up, the both of you, and Iisten.
尼克是从一个
没有希望和前途,
Nicky entered this worId
through the back door,
不见天日的后门
降生人世的.
where hope and promise
never see the Iight.
他妈妈是个贫穷移民
在北方大酒店做清洁女工.
His mother was a poor immigrant
chambermaid at the Great Northern.
他妈妈是因为
被一个偷渡的男人
Nicky was conceived
during an assauIt in a back aIIey
在后巷强暴了
才怀上尼克的.
by a man
who fIed across the border.
她从未向警方报过案
She never reported it to the poIice
但当她来就医时,
她告诉了我.
but when she began to show,
she reported it to me.
但尼克的母亲对自己和她的孩子
的未来有着美好的憧憬.
But Nicky's mother had a dream
of a better Iife for herseIf and her chiId.
她就是带着这个憧憬
来到这个国家.
A dream that she brought with her
to this country.
她决定留下那个孩子.
She decided to carry that chiId.
但这可怜人
没能看上孩子一眼.
But the poor wretch
never saw the boy.
尼克出生那一刻
她就死了.
She died just as Nicky
took his first breath.
我们把她葬在公墓
然后把那个婴儿送到了孤儿院5.
We buried her in potter's fieId
and sent the infant to the orphanage.
几年间, 尼克穿梭于
各个收容所.
For severaI years, Nicky was shuttIed
from one state home to another.
终于有一天,
希望照耀在小尼克身上了.
And then one day,
hope shined on IittIe Nicky.
一对年轻, 无子的夫妇
把他带进了他们的生活.
A young, chiIdIess coupIe
took him into their Iives.
他们是爱心十足, 细心关怀的父母.
They were Ioving, caring parents.
但这一切在一条结冰的高速上
全毁于一旦.
But it aII coIIapsed one terribIe moment
on an icy highway.
是一场车祸.
There was a crash.
6岁大的尼克设法
把父母从着火的车里拖出来,
Six-year-oId Nicky managed
to puII his parents from the bIazing car,
但太迟了.
but it was too Iate.
之后尼克又孤身一人了,
And Nicky was aIone again,
直到现在.
as he is today.
这下我想你们俩高兴了.
I hope you two are happy.
- 詹姆斯, 你这是干嘛?
- 我看起来像在干嘛?
- James, what are you doing?
- What does it Iook Iike I'm doing?
你要走吗? 你要走吗?
Are you Ieaving? Are you Ieaving?
我不能留在这儿.
I can't stay here.
- 我不明白.
- 是错的!
- I don't understand.
- It's wrong!
- 因为我结婚了?
- 是.
- Because I'm married?
- Yes.
是.
Yes.
我爱你, 詹姆斯.
I Iove you, James.
我前半生中
从未对任何人说过这话.
I've never said that
to anybody before in my Iife.
我爱你.
I Iove you.
已经出事了.
There's been an accident.
杰弗里死了.
Jeffrey is dead.
- 他的车?
- 是.
- His car?
- Yes.
你杀了他.
You kiIIed him.
不. 不. 不.
No. No. No.
我的天啊! 你陷害我!
My God! You set me up!
是马科的主意.
他不是我弟弟.
It was MaIcoIm's idea.
He's not my brother.
快跑, 詹姆斯.
Hurry, James.
去找那个爱你的
年轻女孩吧.
Go find that young girI
who Ioves you.
快走.
Go.
詹姆斯?
James?
唐娜?
Donna?
唐娜.
Donna.
我们快跑.
We gotta hurry.
来吧. 来吧.
Come on. Come on.
雪莉在哪儿? 坏女人.
Where is SheIIy? Bad girI.
别怕, 别怕. 进来吧.
No, no. Come in.
没事儿. 我是朋友.
It's aII right. I'm a friend.
进来吧.
Come in.
你样子看来
今晚吃了不少苦头.
You Iook Iike
you've had a very hard night.
过来. 坐啊.
Come. Sit.
我会帮你的.
I wiII heIp you.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
- 里欧.
- 里欧?
- Leo.
- Leo?
好, 里欧.
WeII, Leo.
你可以叫我云顿.
You can caII me Windom.
云顿·厄尔.
Windom EarIe.